<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Health Monitor</string>
    <string name="table_info">» This is the World Health Organization\'s (WHO) recommended body weight based on BMI values for adults. It is used for both men and women, age 20 or older.</string>
    <string name="bmi_info"><![CDATA[• Severe Thinness (<16 kg/m^2)\n• Moderate Thinness (16 - 17 kg/m^2)\n• Mild Thinness (17 - 18.5 kg/m^2)\n• Normal (18.5 - 25 kg/m^2)\n• Overweight (25 - 30 kg/m^2)\n• Obese Class I (30 - 35 kg/m^2)\n• Obese Class II (35 - 40 kg/m^2)\n• Obese Class III (>40 kg/m^2)]]></string>
    <string name="info_1">» Every day you lose water through your breath, perspiration, urine and bowel movements. For your body to function properly, you must replenish its water supply by consuming beverages and foods that contain water.\n\n» So how much fluid does the average, healthy adult living in a temperate climate need? The U.S. National Academies of Sciences, Engineering, and Medicine determined that an adequate daily fluid intake is:</string>
    <string name="info_2">• About 15.5 cups (3.7 liters) of fluids a day for men\n• About 11.5 cups (2.7 liters) of fluids a day for women\n\n» These recommendations cover fluids from water, other beverages and food. About 20% of daily fluid intake usually comes from food and the rest from drinks.</string>
    <string name="bmr_info">» The Basal Metabolic Rate (BMR) Calculator estimates your basal metabolic rate—the amount of energy expended while at rest in a neutrally temperate environment, and in a post-absorptive state (meaning that the digestive system is inactive, which requires about 12 hours of fasting).</string>
    <string name="bmr_test">• BMR TEST : Online BMR tests with rigid formulas are not the most accurate method of determining an individual\'s BMR. It is better to consult a certified specialist or measure BMR through a calorimetry device. These handheld devices are available in many health and fitness clubs, doctor offices, and weight-loss clinics.</string>
    <string name="textInfo1_1">• PCOD (Polycystic Ovarian Disease) is a medical condition in women, where the ovaries produce multiple immature eggs which, over time, become cysts on the ovaries.</string>
    <string name="textInfo1_2">• Ovaries are the reproductive organs of a female which control the menstrual cycle and the production of hormones like estrogen, progesterone, inhibin, relaxin etc. The accumulation of the eggs swells the ovary and makes it release large quantities of male hormone thus causing infertility.</string>
    <string name="textInfo1_3">• PCOD is a hormonal condition that affects approximately 5- 10% of women in their childbearing ages (12 to 45-years). While the prevalence of PCOD differs, it affects around 9% to 22% of Indian women. The numbers are about 2% to 7% in China and Sri Lanka.</string>
    <string name="textInfo1_4">• In this condition, the hormones of a woman go out of balance which creates various symptoms, including the absence of ovulation, irregular menstrual cycle, difficulty conceiving, weight gain, acne, and hirsutism. PCOD, also known as PCOS (Polycystic Ovarian Syndrome), if left untreated, can lead to further health complications, like diabetes, obesity, heart diseases, and high cholesterol.</string>
    <string name="textInfo2_1">• While there is no particular test to confirm PCOD, your doctor would discuss your medical history and perform a physical examination to confirm the condition. They may then recommend</string>
    <string name="textInfo2_2">• A pelvic examination\n• Blood tests to quantify hormone levels\n• An ultrasound to check the appearance of your ovaries and the uterus</string>
    <string name="textInfo2_3">• If you are diagnosed with PCOD, your doctor would suggest regular checkups.</string>
    <string name="textInfo3_1">• Some complications can arise from PCOD. These include various diseases and medical conditions, such as</string>
    <string name="textInfo3_2">• Various metabolic syndromes, including high blood pressure, cardiovascular diseases, increased cholesterol and blood glucose levels.\n• Miscarriages\n• Infertility\n• Gestational diabetes\n• Sleep apnea\n• Type 2 Diabetes\n• Depression and other mental disorders\n• Endometrial cancer\n• Abnormal uterine bleeding\n• Untreatable acne, displaying hormonal problems\n• Chronic Liver inflammation</string>
    <string name="textInfo3_3">• Studies also report that by the age of forty, approximately fifty per cent of women with PCOD would develop pre-diabetes or would already be diabetic, while many others would face infertility during their childbearing age.</string>
    <string name="textInfo4_1">• The cure for PCOD is yet to be determined. However, with proper treatment and lifestyle modifications, you can manage the condition. Your healthcare team is likely to follow a multidisciplinary treatment approach for PCOD. It may include a gynecologist, endocrinologist, dietician, infertility expert, and dermatologist.</string>
    <string name="textInfo4_2">• One of the most practical ways to manage and keep your symptoms in check is proper weight management. Did you know even if you can achieve 5% weight loss, it will make your treatment easy and more effective? Therefore, women who have PCOD must work out regularly and maintain a healthy lifestyle and diet. If you have this condition, make sure to cut on your carbohydrate and sugar and have more high fiber and high protein food.</string>
    <string name="textInfo5_1">• While many lifestyle recommendations are suggested for those women suffering from PCOD, you are encouraged to follow a PCOD diet with low fat and carbohydrate content. This would prevent any sudden upsurge in your blood sugar levels and help you keep a check on your weight. Foods that may be included are</string>
    <string name="textInfo5_2">• Natural, unprocessed food\n• Spinach, kale and other leafy vegetables\n• Foods high in fiber\n• Broccoli and cauliflower\n• Nuts and legumes\n• Fish\n• Whole grain\n• Low-fat dairy</string>
    <string name="textInfo6_1">• If you are suffering from PCOD, then your first task is to reduce your Body Mass Index (BMI). Various types of exercises that you could consider are</string>
    <string name="textInfo6_2">• High-Intensity interval training (HIIT)\n• Cardiovascular workouts\n• Mind-body exercises\n• Strength training\n• Interval training</string>
    <string name="textInfo7_1">• There is no clear cause for PCOD. However, early detection or diagnosis of PCOD will be constructive in relieving the symptoms as well as to reduce the complications involved.</string>
    <string name="textInfo7_2">• PCOD treatment helps you to manage your concerns, including infertility, hirsutism, acne, immature follicles, or obesity. However, specific treatment might involve lifestyle changes or medication.</string>
</resources>